# Deepak Chouhan

Linkedin - Github - Portfolio

Designing things and solving problems are two of my greatest passions. I have developed games as well as websites. I've worked with famous technologies like **Node.JS**, **Express.JS**. I've been concentrating my efforts lately on learning and developing my Data Science and Web development skills.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Technology, Computer science, MIT Art, Design and Technology

2019 - 2023

#### **SKILLS**

Python3, CPP, Django, Java-script, HTML/CSS, Mongodb, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, GitHub, Node.JS, Express.JS, Machine Learning, Googling

### **PROJECTS**

AI-Buddy, Website to help improve commnication skill (Github Link)

Aug 2021 — Dec 2021

- Goal: To develop a website help users to improve their communication and presentation skills.
- Technologies Used: Python, Pandas, Numpy matplotlib, scikit-learn, librosa, Node. JS, Express. JS, Mongodd, oAuth2.0
- Developed front-end for the model and api integration using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Chart.js library to display the overall progress of user.
- oAuth2.0 for better login and signup experience.
- GNews Api for the blog recommendation based on the user's interest to develop their habbit of reading.
- Recommending courses of various leadership qualities for user to learn them.
- Developed a Machine learning models (Speech Emotion recognition, Filler word detector, Speech Accuracy detector) which critique the speech/presentation given by the user.

#### Speech Emotion Classifier, (Github Link)

Aug 2021 — Dec 2021

- Goal: To train a machine learning model which help classify emotions from give audio sample.
- Technologies Used: Python, Pandas, Numpy matplotlib, scikit-learn, librosa
- The purpose of this project is to take the audio file as input and classify emotions ("Calm", "Sad", "Happy", "Fearful", "Angry") in it.
- This Model is part of a project where we analyse the Speech/Presentation given by user with the help of machine learning.
- Used the RAVDESS dataset, which includes audio sample of different actors of both genders which is helpful for better Accuracy.
- Develop a ML Model with the accuracy around **90**% to classify between 5 different emotions.

## **CryptDiary,** Personal details managing website **(Website Link)**

May 2021 — June 2021

- Goal: To Create a Website which allows user to manage their personal details.
- Technologies Used: Node.js, Express.js, Mongodb, oAuth2.0
- Designed and developed the website which allows user to manage their details like Credit/Debit Cards, Accounts of other websites, Addresses
- Implemented oAuth2.0 for better user experience

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Technical Team Member GDSC-MITADT** (Web development)

Sept 2021 — present

- Developed a blog website with an integrated editor so that anyone may publish blogs.
- Collaborating with team members for developing projects and managing events.
- Working on a variety of technologies in order to develop projects.

#### 3D Artist at Eastern Royal Company

Aug 2020 — Nov 2021

- Designing and modelling 3D cars for open world environment.
- Worked with 3D software like **Blender 3D**, **Substance painter** to design 3D assets.

#### PARTICIPATION'S AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Successfully developed and published a 3D Action game built with Unity Engine (Link)

Feb 2021

Open-source participation in Hacktoberfest 2021

Oct 2021

# **PUBLICATIONS**

1. **Deepak**, **C.** Develop Communication using Virtual Reality and Machine Learning. *IRJET* (2022).